Roderick H. Davis Cell: 513-378-4170

Email: roddavis999@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

20+ vears of experience in software development life cycle (Architecture, Design, Coding and Testing of software applications). Highly Proficient in key UI and Full Stack JS technologies: OO JavaScript, Angular, Node, Mongo DB, HTML/CSS, RWD, jQuery, and Bootstrap. Well versed with modern build processes/tools, source control, and agile methodology.

Creative problem solver and team player with a passion for application design and web technologies. Excellent ability to think outside of the box when required, a solid understanding of the full SDLC, and the ability to quickly learn and master new skills and technologies.

COMPUTER LANGUAGES/SOFTWARE EXPERTISE

 MVC pattern NodeJS Junit JavaScript Ajax ColdFusion 7,8 SQL (Including stored procs)
 Java • HTML 3.4.5 SVN/GIT Eclipse • CSS 2, 3 AngularJS Netezza Backbone • Angular 2 jasmine JQuerv • Jasmine
• CSS Frameworks Angular 2MS Office Adobe Photoshop SlickGrid Bootstrap MEAN.js

RECENT PORTFOLIO

** Access to all files and project code is located on my private github repository. Access is available upon request.

Angular 2 – MEAN stack

https://rdavisyoutube.herokuapp.com/#/home

This single-page application (SPA) was created in response to a request for a coding test for a potential job opportunity. Instructions that were provided for the test are listed in the project readme file on github. Feel free to create a user account and search, favorite, like and subscribe to your favorite YouTube videos and channels!

Angular 2 – localStorage and MEAN stack

https://caliberpackaging.com/calibrate

This single-page application (SPA) was created for Caliber Packaging as a way for their service technicians in the field to create work orders for their home office that would then be converted into Purchase Orders. Currently, it is optimized for use on an iPad so it makes heavy use of localStorage. Future plans include conversion to full MEAN stack, connecting to their in-house SAGE software, and an offline mode. Username and password for demo are: username: demo@demo.com and password: demo.

React/React Native/Redux

A few starter projects are available in my repository as these are the latest frameworks I am working on learning. Nothing spectacular yet but you got to start somewhere, right?

WORK EXPERIENCE

Bank of America – On-Site Consultant

(May. 2017 - Aug. 2017)

Senior Front-End Developer for Bank of America's customer facing website www.bankofamerica.com. Worked on the team that developed all code dealing with credit cards. Site is fully responsive and primarily was created using native javascript, ES6, and Foundation. These software's were combined with a custom in-house solution.

ADP – On-Site Consultant

(Dec. 2016 - Mar. 2017)

Full-Stack Developer for Pi next generation payroll services website. Used re-usable components in a test driven development methodology to develop new features for the Pi application. Worked on creating new Angular 2 (w typescript) versions of current Angular

1.5 component library. Wrote Cucumber automation scripts for all new features developed and karma and Jasmine for unit testing of all angular 1.5 components.

Bank of America - On-Site Consultant

(Nov. 2015 - Dec. 2016)

Technical Lead/Senior UI Developer for new Interactive Services Group and Tech Lead for Front-End Developers for CashPro Mobile global banking initiative. Work as Senior UI Developer includes:

Development of re-usable components and widgets for the new Interactive Services group component library. These components are created using AngularJS custom directives. It is the banks goal that all future development will be derived on these components. Currently, we are supporting 5 teams with 4 current applications using the components and 57 more planned by the end of 2017.

- Re-architected and developed a widget framework based on Angular directives that are able to consume generic JSON from backend APIs to render a variety of UI components, including forms, grids (tabular data), charts, and text content.
- Developed efficient techniques to render large tabular sets of data using Angular UI-Grid library.
- Worked with UX team to build proof-of-concept (POC) for Bank of America's OneView transaction reporting software. This is a re-design of the current system to use modern technologies such as AngularJS, Highcharts, and D3.js in an effort to make the site faster and more User Friendly.
- Work on CashPro Mobile application includes the use of AngularJS to create custom directives, services and factories.
- Languages used for UI component work and CashPro Mobile work include extensive AngularJS, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, NodeJS, Bootstrap 3 and Grunt. Additional modules used include angular-ui-router, angular-touch, angular-infinite-scroll and angular-bootstrap.

Tech Lead for CashPro Mobile Initiative include:

- Attend Sprint Grooming sessions to help define stories and break them down into right-sized stories and tasks for my team of 8 onshore and offshore front-end developers.
- Assign tasks to appropriate team member keeping in mind their experience levels and capabilities.
- Work with UX team to develop coding standards and CSS style guide to be used throughout the sprint teams.
- Perform code reviews for work done by each team member during the sprint.
- Mentor junior developers in how to develop best practices and help to define areas and methods of improvement. Mentoring also includes instruction in the use of the new Interactive Services group components.
- Make sure developers are implementing unit tests where applicable.
- Attend daily team lead meeting to discuss and resolve any issues around current application architecture.

Compass Group – On-Site Consultant

(Sept. 2015 - Nov. 2015)

Front-End Developer for Best Vendors Fusion reporting system. Main duties included styling corrections for the site and creation of new functionality for widgets displayed on the site. Most work was done using Kendo UI Widgets, Bootstrap, HTML5, Jquery, and LESS.

Salesforce.com – Remote Consultant

(May. 2015 – Aug. 2015)

UI Developer for MobilePush application. This application is used by major corporations to send mobile messages and notifications to their registered users and clients. The MobilePush application is created using HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Backbone, and Underscore.js.

Bank of America - On-Site Consultant

(Jun. 2014 – April 2015)

Senior UI Developer for in-house financial credit risk reporting software. As part of the Agile Scrum team our goals were to develop new features, maintain existing features, and fix reported bugs from the end-users. Descriptions of key responsibilities are as follows:

Assist project managers and development team to break project into Agile components and determine acceptance criteria and development approach.

- Guided the team in building out a lean, responsive UI layer utilizing semantic html5, SASS, Bootstrap, AngularJS, Jasmine and REST API Architecture while adhering to the latest web UI standards, design patterns, and best practices.
- Worked on custom directives for custom and asynchronous form validations.
- Worked on unit test frameworks such as Mocha, chai, Jasmine and protractor.
- Created project summary reports for business within Confluence application
 which documented the overview of the requested feature, acceptance criteria for
 the development work, design approach, testing approach, and required tasks to
 complete the SDLC.
- Took a leadership role for other team members by helping them with their environment setup, answering questions concerning their assigned projects, the SDLC process at BofA and defect fixes/bug resolution.
- Researched and developed proof-of-concept (POC) to determine which UI grid
 framework the team would use going forward in order to provide Business
 requested functionality within the credit risk reporting application. This work
 included a full presentation to the product owners and development team
 demonstrating the pros and cons of different grid frameworks, the
 recommendation for a particular grid framework, and a fully documented and
 functioning prototype.
- Worked in rotation with the other UI team leads to be the UI representative for software release planning sessions and monthly software releases.
- Languages used included HTML5, CSS3, AngularJS, Javascript, Java, Junit, Ibatis, PowerMock, SQL, Netezza, ExtJS, NG Grid/UI Grid, Slick Grid, Bootstrap

GE Capital Fleet Services – On-Site Consultant (Nov. 2012 – April 2014)

Front-end developer for the GE Capital Fleet Management software application. Responsible for creation and implementation of new features based on determined functionality guidelines. Works with SCRUM team members and project managers to identify, define, and execute application changes and enhancements. Front-End development work is done following an MVC framework with an eye on continuous integration and responsive design. Languages/development tools used include Javascript, JQuery, Backbone.js, Bootstrap.js, Require.js, Underscore.js, Knockout.js, HTML 5, CSS 3, Jasmine, Grunt, Node.js and Eclipse.

Discover Financial Services – On-Site Consultant (Mar. 2012 – Jun. 2012)

Technical lead for in-house scheduling and reporting software creation and maintenance following a MVC framework. Responsible for creation of new modules, writing of project proposals, and being liaison between technical team and non-technical project members.

Languages/development tools used included ColdFusion, JQuery, CSS, HTML 5.

Gensuite, LLC – On-Site Consultant

(Oct. 2011 – Feb. 23, 2012)

Created new modules and helped maintain existing applications for the Gensuite suite of products. Also provided direct customer support for current applications. Languages/development tools used include ColdFusion, Javascript, CSS, HTML. Originally was scheduled to be a 6 month contract that I completed early

Possible Worldwide – On-Site Consultant (Aug. 2011 – Oct. 2011)

Responsible for creation of custom Facebook application for popular yogurt website. Also worked on updates to numerous other websites and database creation/maintenance for Dannon's Rally for Recess promotion. Languages/development tools used include C#.NET, Ajax Toolkit, Facebook Open Graph API, SQL server, Visual studio and Tortoise SVN. Limited use of JQuery modules.

Web4One Designs, Ltd. Owner and Lead Programmer

Cincinnati, OH January 2002 – Sept. 2010

- Responsible for creation of numerous web sites and databases for a variety of businesses and services. Most sites were created using different combinations of HTML, Javascript, CSS, ASP/ASP.NET and SQL or MySQL databases. Some sites incorporated elements of Flash/Actionscript and XML databases.
- Responsible for site design and logo design for the majority of the web sites created. All design work was done using Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop and in some cases Adobe InDesign.
- · Creation and implementation of all print, online and e-mail marketing campaigns.
- Oversee all sales, consulting, copyediting and administrative functions.

Work samples include:

Job Screening Coding Challenge – <u>www.web4onedesigns.com/codetest</u> (Completed Apr. 2015)

The above link is to the results of a coding challenge I was asked to complete as part of the Interview process for an AngularJS position. The challenge was for me to use the supplied .psd and .jpeg files (Link to provided .jpeg file) to create as much of the site as possible in 72 hours. It was also a test to see how I interpreted what I saw and what features/functionality I would include given such vague instructions. The site is done completely with AngularJS, HTML5, CSS3, Grunt, and the MEAN stack generator. For the data, it reads a JSON file and stores that information into localStorage to increase performance.

Anderson Publishing Co. Senior Programmer

Cincinnati, OH April 1997 – December 2002

- · Responsible for design and creation of online research web site
- · Created and maintained databases for all electronic and online products
- · Created software installations for CD-ROM products
- Provided technical support to customers for more complicated problems and network issues that could not be answered by the technical support department
- · Served as troubleshooter for hardware problems or issues affecting the Editorial Department

EDUCATIONAL EXPERIENCE

Wright State University

Dayton, OH 1989-1996

- Dual Major—Computer Science and English
- · National Merit Scholarship Recipient
- Member of Division I Men's Varsity Soccer Team